Evan Madden

(856) 571 - 4345 | evan.madden@gmail.com | Philadelphia, PA 19148 GitHub: /EvMad | Portfolio: https://evmad.github.io/portfolio-one/ LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/evan-madden-923474211/

Summary:

Full Stack Web developer with a music industry background, a Web Development Certificate from the University of Pennsylvania LPS bootcamp, and a BA in Music Technology. Currently completing a UX Design Certificate through Google Coursera. Soft skills developed over a decade of managing client experience and event production.

Technical Skills, Languages, and Frameworks:

HTML, HTML5, XML, XHTML, Markup, PHP, Regex, htaccess, CSS, SCSS, Sass, CSS frameworks, Bulma, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ECMAScript6, ES6, ES13, JSX, vanilla JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, OOP, Git, Git Bash, version control, CLI, Github, Heroku, deployment, FTP, MERN, React, React Router, Redux, React Hooks, DOM, Virtual DOM, Node.js, Node, NPM, Inquirer.js, Moment.js, Webpack, PWA, Progressive Web App, ServiceWorker.js, Manifest, Responsive Web Design, Express, Express.js, API, APIs, RESTful, REST, Ajax, Insomnia Core, Handlebars.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, GraphQL, Apollo, Apollo Server, Atlas, MongoDB Atlas, non-relational database, SQL, MySQL, Workbench, Sequelize, Sequelize.js, relational database, SOQL, Salesforce, Apex, Visualforce, AutoRabit, CRM, Kanban, Trello, Jira, Azure DevOps, DevOps, AWS, Scrum, Agile, WCAG, Accessibility, User Centered Design, Adobe XD, Figma, UX, UI, UX/UI, UI/UX, UX Research, UX Design, User Stories, Personas, DCM, Cloudinary, Digital Content Management

Relevant Employment:

Web Specialist : ECFMG Philadelphia, PA July 2022 - Present

Responsible for maintaining five websites, accessibility, optimizing page speed, developing remotely within a team using Git version control, completing work packets through Trello, attending daily huddles, standups, and planning meetings to coordinate with editorial staff.

• Tools: Trello, Azure DevOps, Microsoft Teams, HTML, PHP, JavaScript, Bulma, Sass, SCSS, CSS, Wordpress, XHTML, XML, htaccess, Regex, Apache, Git Bash, AutoRabit, Salesforce, Markup, Microsoft Word, Adobe, Photoshop, User Stories, UX

Bar Manager: Kung Fu Necktie Philadelphia, PA March 2015 - July 2022 Promoted from bartender to keyholder to manager for a live music venue. Coordinated event staff (booking, security, sound, and bar.) Engaged and retained new clients.

• Tools: Google Calendar, Google Sheets, PrismFM, Social Media, Ticket Fly, Eventbrite

Education:

University of Pennsylvania - Full Stack Web Development Certificate May 2021 - August 2021

Google Coursera - UX Design Certificate October 2021 - October 2022

University of Maryland Baltimore County - BA in Music, Recording Emphasis Linehan Artist Scholar Program

Projects:

React Blog

Deployed: https://bit.ly/3dvfEmL Repo: https://bit.ly/3dvfEmL React and Node front-end blog mockup, deployed via Heroku.

Case Study

Deployed: https://bit.ly/3qWbo2R Repo: https://bit.ly/3pJd5IK

UX Case Study including UX research, personas, wireframes, usability studies, prototypes, mockups, and sticker sheets. Made using Figma and Adobe XD, as well as a deployed gallery through Github, built with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Community Canvas

Deployed: https://bit.ly/3k2TZCE

Community Canvas is a full stack application developed for users to upload and view photos of street art, created with JavaScript, Sequelize, and MySQL. This role focused on learning to use Cloudinary as a digital assets management platform, as well as creating a mobile-first design.